SLEIMAN KOUEIK

slaiman_koeik@hotmail.com
Masters of research in Computer Science and IDSS
(Information & Decision Support Systems)



Personal Information

Last name/First name KOUEIK, Sleiman

Phone +961-71-339750

E-mail(s) slaiman_koeik@hotmail.com

Marital Status Single

Nationality Lebanese

Date and Place of birth 26 November 1988, Beirut - Lebanon

Work Stay Work permit in France for 2 years (30-12-2023)

Profile

During my experience in software development, my curiosity and commercial experience gave me various skills in different programming languages and platforms. Moreover, I am ambitious, dynamic, quick learner and hardworking.

I worked for a lot of projects like content management systems, E-commerce systems, Medical systems, Banking systems, Insurance systems etc....., During my work in these projects I gained a lot of experience in Integration using API (mainly Restful) and development of these API's.

Areas of Expertise

- Algorithms & Data Structure
- Business Process Management
- Big Data
- Stream Processing
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- Data Management
- No-SQL Database
- Data Integration
- Mobile Computing

Education & Diplomas

Masters 2 research in Computer Science

2015 - 2016

Lebanese University; LIRIS research Lab Claude Bernard University (Lyon 1)

Resume – Sleiman Koueik, MS (CS)

Thesis

Streaming Activity Logs of complex end-to-end logistics process and

IOT data into scalable cluster.

http://cognitus.fr/research-showcase/

http://cognitus.fr/research-showcase//InSFram

Bachelor in Computer and Communication Engineering (CCE)

2008 - 2014

Faculty of Engineering, IUL University

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2022 – Present

Lyst Technologies

Responsible for:

- -Implement and design dynamic soap engine-Enhancing the Core system Registry Module.
- -Design and implement parsing engine module for ISO 8583 protocol into 3 main parts (parser service, parser entities classes, utilty classes).
- -integrating soap engine with core banking
- -integrating iso 8583 financial protocol with core banking.
- -Design and implement Swift parsing system (swift parser service class, parser entities, utility classes).

Tech Stack: Java 10, Spring boot, Multi-threading, Sockets programming, JDBC, HTML, CSS3, XML, jQuery, AJAX, SQL, SVN, Maven, CSS, SOAP web service, Restful web service, MuleSoft.

Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2021 – July 2022

Noema Consulting - Partner with Axxiome digital, Beirut

Responsible for:

- -Implementing Unit tests using Mockito and Junit to test the core System.
- -Enhancing the Core system Registry Module.
- -Enhancing the Core system Pipelines module.
- -design and implement Kafka consumer Module to consume events generated by Soap web service (consumer service, utility class).
- -Integrating core Banking Modules using Restful API's and EJB.

Tech Stack: J2EE, Multi-threading, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, HTML5, CSS3, XML, jQuery, AJAX, SQL, PL/SQL, Redis server, Maven archetype, SVN, Git, Maven, HTML5, CSS, SOAP web service, Restful web service.

Senior lead Java Engineer (remote job)

June 2018 – July 2021

Randem Group, Beirut

Responsible for the implementation and enhancement of middleware:

- -implementing amazon EC3 and SQS components for log storage.
- -design and implement middleware core using spring boot and data jpa.
- -design and implement middleware cache using Redis.
- -design and implement MySQL component for database.
- -design and implement amazon dynamoDb component for data tracking and syncing.
- -Integration of E-commerce system with the middleware using Restful webservice.
- -Integration of Middleware and company's systems using Restful web service.
- -deploy on cloud system log data on AWS dynamoDB.
- -deploy on cloud transactional data on AWS SQS, AWS EC2, AWS EC3.
- -Deploy on cloud error data on AWS MySQL.

Tech Stack: JavaEE, spring boot, spring data, spring mvc, hibernate, amazon SQS, amazon EC3, Redis Server, amazon

DynamoDB, mySQL, restful web service, XML, wildFLy web server, linux, Shell scripting, JIRA, SVN, Git, Maven.

Senior Team Lead Software Engineer

Dec 2014 – May 2018

Everteam – Team Lead for Algeria Team

Design & Develop business & Product features for Algerian Projects "Sorfert" & "GRN" using J2EE Technology.

- -Developing DMS product a Document Management System using J2EE platform.
- -Developing business & product features on DMS product.
- -Development + integration of Saml 2 authentication method using OpenSAML V3 tool.
- -responsible for Support and enhancement for DMS products regrading "Sorfert" and "GRN" customers.

Tech Stack: J2EE, JSE, SQL, JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, CSS, FreeMarker, OpenSaml V3, PostgreSQL, Windows Server 2012, TDD, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, CVS.

BPM Java Developer (Remote work)

Jan 2012- Nov. 2014

Resume – Sleiman Koueik, MS (CS)

RSTN Consulting

- 1-Design & implement Business process management systems for Insurance Companies.
- 2-Design & Implement Web Services in terms of Restful & SOAP.

3-Design & Implement Event Response System using BizFlow ERA (Event Response Adapter) that uses java technologies (JSP, DOM Library) to consume XML & XSD data, process, store and output the result for BizFlow Server and other Systems.

4-participate in customer support for Metlife company in Poland.

Tech Stack: J2EE, JSE, SQL, JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, CSS, JSP, BPMN (BizFlow Server, BizFlow ERA), RestFul Webservice, SOAP UI, XML, XSD, Windows Server 2012, TDD, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, SVN.

Key attributes

- Quick Learner and poses the ability to work under pressure
- Possess good management and organizational skills
- Sound knowledge of recognizing and analyzing problems

Technical Skills

Languages Java, C/C++, Perl, Matlab, VB.net, Vba (excel), Android, C#, UML, MS Excel.

Web related Asp.net, MVC, ADO.Net, XML, XSD, JSON, HTML5, JSP, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax,

JQuery, Bootstrap, Entity Framework.

Web Servers Apache Tomcat, IIS.

Web Services Restful & SOAP.

Natural Language Processing (NLP) Stanford NLP Tool.

Authentication tools OpenSaml V3.

Web Ontology Languages RDF, RDFS, OWL.

Semantic Web Technology SPARQL.

Big Data Frameworks Apache Hadoop, Apache Storm, Apache Spark.

Big Data Platforms Apache Kafka, Apache Flume.

Business Process Management tools Activiti, BizFlow

DBMS SQL, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

NoSQL MongoDB, Apache Hbase.

Operating System Linux (Ubuntu), Windows OS, Windows server 2012.

IDE Eclipse, Netbeans, Android Studio, Visual Studio, IntelliJ.

Others Tortoise SVN, Microsoft Teams, Open VPN GUI, Skype for business, JIRA, Slack

Languages

English Good verbal and written communication skills.

Arabic Native Language.

Interest and Hobbies

Exploring the latest technology trends.

Reading Novels and books.

Internet freedom and online privacy.

Swimming.

References

H.ABDALLAH@EVERTEAM-GS.COM Hussein abdallah, Country Manager at EverTeam.

Yehia.taher@uvsq.fr Yehia TAHER, Associate Professor at the University of Versailles Saint-

Quentin-en-Yvelines, France, CEO of Cognitus Company (75011 Paris,

France)..

<u>rafiq.ced@gmail.com</u> CTO of Cognitus Company (75011 Paris, France).